Hello, everyone. So today we are going to talk about demand paging. And before starting,
大家好。今天我们要讨论的是需求分页。在开始之前，
thanks a lot, everyone, for filling in the survey about the class. Great feedback. And
非常感谢大家填写关于课程的调查问卷。非常宝贵的反馈。而且
we are going to try to act on it. So before, let me start with this same figure, which
我们将尝试采取行动。所以在此之前，让我从这个相同的数字开始，它是...
I think you went over last lecture. But let me do it again, because it's a very important
我觉得你上次的讲座内容有点超过了。但是让我再来一次，因为这非常重要。
figure, because with everything together, all the memory related concepts we have learned
图形，因为将所有与内存相关的概念整合在一起，我们所学到的。
so far. And as always, if you have any questions, please do not hesitate to let me know. So
到目前为止。如往常一样，如果你有任何问题，请随时告诉我。
here we have the virtual address on the left. And you remember the virtual address is what
这里我们在左边有虚拟地址。而你记得虚拟地址是什么吗？
the programs and what the processor sees. And the right hand side, you have the physical
程序和处理器所看到的内容。右侧是物理的。
memory address. And what we learn, we learn about the address translation in which these
内存地址。我们所学的是关于地址转换的内容，其中这些地址
virtual addresses are translated to physical addresses. And one way we did that is through
虚拟地址被翻译成物理地址。我们其中一种方法是通过...
multi-level paging. In this example, we are showing two level paging. And therefore, the
多级分页。在这个例子中，我们展示了两级分页。因此，
virtual address consists of three fields. The last one, the blue is blue in this figure,
虚拟地址由三个字段组成。最后一个字段，在这个图中是蓝色的。
is the offset. And the offset, the bit in the offset remains unchanged in the physical
是偏移量。而且，偏移量中的位在物理上保持不变。
address. And then the first field of the virtual address, it's an index to the first level
地址
in the first level page table. And at that address in the first, at that location in
在第一级页表中。并且在第一个地址，在那个位置上。
the first page table, you find the address of another page table at the second level.
在第一页的表格中，你会找到第二级的另一个页表的地址。
And the second field in the address, the virtual P2 index, denoted here, it's an index to the
地址中的第二个字段，虚拟P2索引，在这里表示，它是一个指向的索引。
second level page table, which is referenced from the first level page table. And as a
第二级页表，它是从一级页表中引用的。而且作为一个
corresponding location in the second level page table, you have the physical page number.
在第二级页表中对应的位置
And now you concatenate the physical page number with the offset, and you got the physical
页码与偏移量相连，你就得到了物理页码。
address. Okay? It's the physical page number, as you see here depicted, and the offset represents
地址。好吗？这是物理页码，就像你在这里看到的那样，偏移量表示
the offset within that page. So this is virtual address, the address translation from virtual
该页内的偏移量。所以这是虚拟地址，是从虚拟地址转换过来的地址。
addresses to physical addresses using two-level paging. Okay? In addition, what you also learn
将逻辑地址转换为物理地址使用两级分页。好吗？另外，你还学到了什么？
about is about translation lookaside buffers. Okay? Can someone tell me why do we need a
关于翻译查找缓冲区。好吗？有人能告诉我为什么我们需要它吗？
translation lookaside buffer or TLB for short? What problem does it solve? It's exact. Thanks,
翻译后的结果：translation lookaside buffer，简称TLB。它解决了什么问题？确切的说。谢谢。
Alison and Gilbert. You are correct. So fundamentally, as you see, with the two-level page tables,
艾莉森和吉尔伯特。你们是正确的。所以从根本上来说，正如你们所看到的，使用两级页表，
you need in order to do the translation, you need to do multiple memory accesses. We need
你需要进行翻译，你需要进行多次内存访问。我们需要什么？
to get a location from the first level page table, then to access the second level page
从一级页表中获取一个位置，然后访问二级页。
table, there are a bunch, this means a bunch of memory accesses. Right? So when you are
桌子，有很多，这意味着很多内存访问。对吗？所以当你...
going to look to a physical, to try to just look at location in memory, to fetch an instruction
我要去查看一个物理位置，试图直接查看内存中的位置，以获取一条指令。
or to access data, you have to do multiple memory accesses, which is very slow. Right?
或者说要访问数据，你需要进行多次内存访问，这样会非常慢。对吗？
So translation lookaside buffer solve this problem. So it's a small table, which takes
因此，翻译查找缓冲区解决了这个问题。它是一个小表，用于存储翻译结果。
a virtual address, you know, that takes the first two fields in the virtual address, which
一个虚拟地址，你知道的，它取虚拟地址的前两个字段，这些字段是什么？
contains a page information and maps that to the physical page number. So the, and this
包含页面信息并将其映射到物理页面号码。所以，这个...
is happening, it's in hardware, so the translation is very quick. This TLB is in the processor.
发生了，它是硬件上的，所以翻译非常快。这个TLB在处理器中。
And then what is the other way we are going to try to improve the performance? Because
然后我们还有什么其他方法来尝试提高性能呢？因为
even if we make one access to the RAM, to the memory, the time to make that access,
即使我们对RAM或内存进行一次访问，访问所需的时间也是...
the latency is much larger than accessing say registers or in the processor. It's order
延迟比访问寄存器或处理器要大得多。它的数量级是多少？
of magnitude slower to access physical memory. So to solve this problem, what you learned
is to use a cache. A cache is a smaller, faster memory that stores copies of frequently accessed data from the main memory. By storing this data closer to the processor, it can be accessed much faster, reducing the time it takes to retrieve data from the main memory.
last lecture, we can and also at 61C earlier on, it's about you are using cache, right?
上一堂课，我们讲了61C的内容，是关于你们使用缓存的对吗？
A cache. So cache, it's a smaller memory. And because it's smaller, it can be either
缓存。所以缓存，它是一个较小的内存。由于它较小，它可以是以下两种情况之一：
closer or it can be directly on the chip on the processor. So therefore the latency to
更近一些，或者可以直接在处理器芯片上。因此，延迟可以更低。
access this cache is much lower than the latency to access the physical memory. So if the data
访问这个缓存的延迟比访问物理内存的延迟要低得多。因此，如果数据
you are looking for is already in cache, the access will be much quicker. And here we show
你要找的已经在缓存中了，访问会快很多。这里我们展示
set associative cache. You remember that the set associative cache, you have multiple sets
组相联缓存。你记得组相联缓存，你有多个组。
of this kind of multiple sets of blocks. And each of them is identified by attack. And
这种多组方块的类型。每个方块组都通过攻击来识别。
within each set, you can associatively identify one of these, here is represented by a line,
在每个集合中，你可以通过联想识别其中一个，这里用一条线表示。
one of these rows. Okay. And how do you do that? So now the cache is addressed with a
这些行中的一行。好的。那么你如何做到这一点呢？现在缓存的地址是通过一个
physical address. So the physical address now is divided into other three fields, which
物理地址。所以现在物理地址被分成了其他三个字段，它们是：
is very tag, index and byte. And the index, if you have a memory set associative cache,
是非常标签、索引和字节。而且，如果你有一个集合关联的缓存内存，索引的话，
the index points to a particular set of such rows. And then the tag is going to identify
索引指向一组特定的行。然后标签将用于标识。
a row in the set. And finally, or in a byte will specify a index of the byte you are looking
一行在集合中。最后，或者在一个字节中将指定你正在查找的字节的索引。
for in that row. So also we also refer it as a block to these rows. Okay. So this is
在那一行中。因此，我们也将这些行称为一个块。好的。所以这就是
it. Okay. So you have address translation. To speed up the address translation, you use
它。好的。所以你有地址转换。为了加快地址转换速度，你使用了什么方法？
a TLB, which maps in hardware, the virtual page number to the physical page number. And
一个TLB，它在硬件中将虚拟页号映射到物理页号。
then to further speed up the access to the memory, we use cache, a cache. And to locate
然后为了进一步加快对内存的访问速度，我们使用缓存，一个缓存。而为了定位
the data in the cache, we use these three fields, tag, index and byte. Any questions?
缓存中的数据，我们使用这三个字段，标签、索引和字节。有任何问题吗？
Just remember that the TLB, you address a TLB with a virtual page number and you address
只需记住，TLB是通过虚拟页号进行寻址的。
a cache with a physical address. So now the one question, if you remember, is that the
一个带有物理地址的缓存。现在只有一个问题，如果你还记得的话，那就是
virtual address space can be larger than the physical address. Also, you have multiple
虚拟地址空间可以比物理地址更大。此外，您还可以拥有多个
virtual address spaces, which are going to multiplex the same physical address because
虚拟地址空间，将会对同一个物理地址进行多路复用，因为
each process has its own virtual address space. Okay. So this means that at a given time,
每个进程都有自己的虚拟地址空间。好的。这意味着在某个特定的时间，
you may not be able to store all the virtual address, all the data in the virtual address
你可能无法存储所有的虚拟地址，所有虚拟地址中的数据。
space across all processes in the physical memory. And if you cannot do that, some of
在物理内存中跨所有进程的空间。如果你无法做到这一点，那么一些
these pages, you need to put somewhere else. Typically somewhere else is on the disk or
这些页面，你需要放在其他地方。通常其他地方指的是磁盘上或者
SSD. So now the question is about when you need a page, which is not in the memory, it's
SSD。现在的问题是，当你需要一个不在内存中的页面时，它是什么时候的。
on the disk. How do you go about getting that page in memory? Okay. That's what we are going
在磁盘上。你如何将那个页面加载到内存中？好的。这就是我们要做的事情。
to learn and focus on is the remaining of this lecture. And when we are going to access
学习和专注是本讲座的剩余内容。当我们要访问时，
a page, which is not in physical memory, then what happens, you have a page fault. And the
当一个页面不在物理内存中时，会发生什么情况，你会遇到一个页面错误。然后，系统会将该页面从磁盘加载到内存中。
way this is indicated, remember that when you do the address translation, you look in
这是如何指示的，请记住，当你进行地址转换时，你要查找的是
the page table. In the page table, you find a page table entry corresponding to that page.
页表。在页表中，你会找到与该页对应的页表项。
So that page table entry has a bit, which is saying, for instance, it's invalid bit.
所以这个页表项有一个位，比如说，它是无效位。
And if that bit is set, this means that the page is not present in the physical memory.
如果该位被设置，这意味着该页面不在物理内存中。
Okay. So now a page fault will occur and what happens? Okay. So on page fault, you will
好的。那么现在会发生一个页面错误，接下来会发生什么？好的。当发生页面错误时，你将会发生什么？
have to engage the operating system and the operating system will make sure to bring the
必须启动操作系统，操作系统会确保将其带来。
right page from the disk to memory. So then you are going to be able to continue the execution
将磁盘上的正确页面加载到内存中。然后你就可以继续执行了。
of the program. Of course, to bring a page from the disk to the physical memory, you
程序的一部分。当然，将页面从磁盘加载到物理内存中，你需要
need to find a place to put it. If you have free space, you bring it in, you bring it
需要找一个地方放它。如果你有空闲的空间，你就把它带进来，你就把它带进来。
up. If you don't have free space, they need to take an existing page and replace it with
向上。如果你没有空闲空间，他们需要拿走一个已有的页面并用它替换。
a new page you want to bring in memory. Now, if that page you want to replace has been
一个你想要存入内存的新页面。现在，如果你想要替换的页面已经存在
written, has been modified, then you need to put it on the disk, save it on the disk
写好后，需要进行修改，然后将其放入磁盘上，保存在磁盘上。
before you replace it with a new page. Okay. So that's what it is. We are going to go through
在你用新页面替换之前。好的。那就是它的意思。我们要经历一下。
this process several times during this lecture to make sure that the concepts are clear.
在这次讲座中，要多次进行这个过程，以确保概念清晰。
And before going forward, notice that it's a fundamental inversion here that you have
而在继续之前，请注意这里发生了一个基本的颠倒，你已经拥有了。
the hardware. The hardware causes a page fault in this case because the invalid bit on the
硬件。在这种情况下，硬件会引发页面错误，因为无效位在该页上。
page table entry set, which then this fault is treated in software, right? As opposed
页面表项集，然后这个错误在软件中处理，对吗？与之相反的是什么？
to interrupts, where the interrupts are treated in hardware. And then once you select the
中断，其中中断在硬件中处理。然后一旦你选择了
handle of the interrupt, only then you go into software. Okay. So again, to put things
中断处理程序的处理，然后才进入软件。好的。所以再次，为了搞清楚事情的情况，
into perspective right now, this is you have different levels of memory or storage. You
现在来看，你有不同层次的记忆或存储。
have on-chip cache here is a processor and in today's processors, you actually have multiple
在这里有一个片上缓存，它是一个处理器。在今天的处理器中，实际上有多个。
caches, level of caches, even on a single processor, because you may have a cache for
缓存，缓存级别，即使在单个处理器上，因为你可能有一个用于缓存的缓存。
each core. And then you may have a unified cache, which is across all cores. Then you
每个核心。然后你可能会有一个统一的缓存，它跨越所有核心。然后你
have second level cache. It's a main memory. Then is this like secondary storage. And then
有第二级缓存。它是主内存。那么这就像是辅助存储器。然后呢？
of course you can even have tertiary storage, tape or some kind of storage in the cloud.
当然可以，甚至可以使用三级存储，磁带或云中的某种存储方式。
Okay. So the key here, what is the key here? What we are trying to do is caching with everything
好的。所以关键是什么？我们试图做的是将所有东西缓存起来。
else. We're trying to do something very simple. Yeah. We want to try to have the cake and
else. 我们正在尝试做一些非常简单的事情。是的。我们想尝试既要有蛋糕，又要
eat it too. So you want to have, we want to build a system which behaves like it has a
吃饱又想吃。所以你想要拥有，我们想要构建一个行为就像拥有的系统。
storage of the largest storage device it has access to, but the latency to access that
它可以访问的最大存储设备的存储容量，但访问该设备的延迟时间。
storage it's the same as accessing the on-chip cache. That's a holy grail. Right? And again,
存储就是访问芯片上的缓存。这是一个圣杯，对吗？再说一遍，
the key here is that at every level, the key technique is using caching. You cache the
关键在于，在每个层面上，关键技术是使用缓存。你将缓存
data from the next level and you hope that for the vast majority of time, the program
数据来自下一个级别，你希望在绝大部分时间里，该程序能够
will only use the data in that cache. You don't go to the next level. Okay. And if the
只会使用缓存中的数据。不会去下一层。好的。如果
program execute locality, so therefore he spends most of the time in a reasonably small
程序执行的局部性，因此他大部分时间都在一个相对较小的范围内。
portion of the code or touching small portion of the data, you are in luck because as long
如果你只需要处理代码的一部分或者只需要涉及到数据的一小部分，那么你很幸运，因为只要
as you put this heavily accessed region of memory of a program in the cache, you are
将程序中这个频繁访问的内存区域放入缓存中时，你就是在
fine.
好的。
And the last point to make here is a way to think about the main memory. It says a cache
而在这里要提到的最后一点是关于主内存的一种思考方式。它说的是一个缓存。
for the secondary storage for the disk. Right? It's again, at each level, you can think it's
对于磁盘的辅助存储。对吗？在每个层级上，你可以认为它是
a cache for the next level. But we don't call it cache. We call it paging. So here is again,
下一级的缓存。但我们不称之为缓存，而是称之为分页。所以这里再次提到，
another figure showing you the page fault. What I described earlier in words, this is
另一个图表显示了页面错误。我之前用文字描述的内容，这就是。
using some animation to drive the point home. So say you have an instruction and you do
使用一些动画来强调重点。比如说你有一条指示，你可以通过动画来展示。
the instruction fetch, then you go to the memory management unit. The memory management
指令获取，然后你进入内存管理单元。内存管理
unit, it handles the page table, TLB and all of this great stuff to do address translation.
单元，它处理页表、TLB和所有这些很棒的东西来进行地址转换。
And now you go, you find the page table entry and then from the page entry, you are going
然后你继续，找到页表项，然后从页表项中，你继续前进。
to have the page number and the offset. The offset keeps coming from the virtual address,
要有页码和偏移量。偏移量来自虚拟地址。
the page number comes after translation.
页码在翻译之后。
But now let's assume that you do when you execute the next instruction, you go to the
但是现在假设当你执行下一条指令时，你会去到...
page table, but the entry doesn't exist or it exists and it's invalid. So then you have
页表，但该条目不存在或存在但无效。因此，您有
a page fault. So you go to the operating system to take care of things. The operating system
一个页面错误。所以你去操作系统处理事情。操作系统
on fault is going to do what? It's going basically to load, to locate the page on the disk, which
故障会做什么？它基本上会加载，将页面定位到磁盘上，然后
is required by the program, load that page in the physical memory and then update the
程序要求，将该页面加载到物理内存中，然后更新。
page table entry. And finally, you restart the program and the program will retry the
页面表项。最后，您重新启动程序，程序将重试。
previous instruction, which calls a page fault. Now the previous instruction is going to have
先前的指令引发了页面错误。现在，先前的指令将会有...
the same look to do the same page from the same virtual address. But now the page is
相同的外观从相同的虚拟地址执行相同的页面。但现在页面是什么？
already in the memory. So you are going to access that page and continue execution. Is
已经在内存中。因此，您将访问该页面并继续执行。
that clear? Any questions?
明白了吗？有什么问题吗？
So now we just said that the main page paging is like caching. The memory act as a cache
所以现在我们刚刚说过，主页的分页就像缓存一样。内存充当缓存。
for the persistent storage like disk or SSD. So now let's look from the point of view of
对于持久存储，比如磁盘或固态硬盘（SSD）。现在让我们从以下角度来看。
the caching, from the point of view of a cache and characterize the demand paging. First
缓存，从缓存的角度来看，可以描述为需求分页。首先
of all, what is the block size? What is the cache granularity? The block size, it's basically
首先，块大小是多少？缓存的粒度是多少？块大小，基本上是指数据块的大小。
in this case, as you know, it's one page, which is say four kilobytes, between one kilobytes
在这种情况下，正如你所知道的，这是一页，大约四千字节，相当于一千千字节之间。
and 16 kilobytes. What is your organization of the cache? We learned about direct map
和16千字节。你的缓存组织是什么？我们学习了直接映射。
cache, fully associative.
高速缓存，全关联。
set associative.
组相联。
And the answer here is that it's fully associative.
答案是它是完全可结合的。
Fully associative provides you the most,
全关联提供给你最多的
is the most efficient in using the cache, if you remember.
如果你还记得的话，它是在使用缓存方面最高效的。
Why?
为什么？
Why is a fully associative memory
为什么是全关联存储器？
the most effective in using the cache storage?
在使用缓存存储方面最有效的方法是什么？
Yes, you can place it anywhere.
是的，你可以把它放在任何地方。
So there are no conflicts.
所以没有冲突。
There are no conflict misses.
没有冲突缺失。
Like you remember, it's direct mapped cache.
就像你记得的那样，这是直接映射缓存。
You have conflict misses.
你有冲突遗漏。
You don't have conflict misses here with associative cache.
你在这里使用关联缓存不会出现冲突缺失。
Okay.
Sure. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
There is a question here.
这里有一个问题。
So the page fault we see in the error message
所以在错误信息中看到的页面错误
happened on the demand paging,
发生在需求分页上，
does not save the program.
不保存程序。
Okay.
Sure, I'll do my best to assist you with your translations. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
Maybe you can ask again the question.
也许你可以再问一遍这个问题。
I'm afraid I do not understand what error
我很抱歉，我不明白你说的是什么错误。
we are talking about here.
我们正在这里谈论。
We are talking about the, yeah,
我们正在谈论，是的，
please ask the question again,
请再次提出问题。
and I'll be happy to answer.
我很乐意回答。
So now how do you locate the page?
那么现在你如何定位这个页面呢？
First, you check the TLB.
首先，你检查TLB。
Then you do the page traversal if it's not in the TLB.
如果在TLB中找不到，那么你需要进行页面遍历。
Right?
对吗？
This is how you locate the page.
这是你定位页面的方法。
What is a page replacement policy?
页面置换策略是指在计算机操作系统中，当内存中的页面不足时，选择哪些页面被替换出去，以便为新的页面腾出空间。
As you'll see, we want ALEREO,
正如您所看到的，我们想要ALEREO。
at least recently used.
至少最近使用过。
We are going to look at other replacement policies,
我们将研究其他的替代政策，
but typically we try to have an approximation of ALEREO,
但通常我们会尽量接近ALEREO的近似值。
and we have to have an approximation of ALEREO
并且我们需要对ALEREO进行近似。
because you just implemented ALEREO can be too expensive.
因为你刚刚实施ALEREO可能会太昂贵。
We'll learn about that.
我们会了解这个。
What happened on a miss?
发生了什么事情？
You saw that, right?
你看到了，对吗？
When there is a miss,
当出现错误时，
you are going to find the page on the disk
你要在磁盘上找到那个页面。
and bring the page in the memory.
并将页面加载到内存中。
What happens on a write?
写操作会发生什么？
Remember that the cache has a copy of the data from memory.
请记住，缓存中存有来自内存的数据副本。
So if you modify the data in the cache,
那么如果你修改了缓存中的数据，
you need also to modify the copy of that data in memory.
你还需要修改内存中的数据副本。
And there are two ways to modify it.
并且有两种方法可以修改它。
One is write through.
一个是写透的。
This means that as soon as you update the cache,
这意味着一旦你更新缓存，
also you update the main memory.
还有，你需要更新主内存。
The second method is write back.
第二种方法是写回。
You just update the cache.
你刚刚更新了缓存。
And when you want to replace the data in the cache
并且当你想要替换缓存中的数据时
with some other data to bring it in,
带上其他一些数据来补充进去，
then you are going to write back the data
那么你将会回传数据。
from the cache to the memory before replacing it.
将缓存中的内容写回内存，然后再替换。
In this case, we are talking about memory on the disk.
在这种情况下，我们正在谈论磁盘上的存储空间。
We are definitely talking about write back.
我们肯定在谈论写回。
Why write back in this case?
为什么在这种情况下要写回来呢？
Tell me.
告诉我。
Why don't we do write through?
为什么我们不采用写透模式？
(silence)
对不起，我无法翻译沉默。请提供需要翻译的具体内容。
Yes, excellent.
是的，非常好。
So, Alison and Tyrell.
所以，Alison和Tyrell。
So this is because it's very expensive
所以这是因为它非常昂贵。
to read the data from the disk.
读取磁盘上的数据。
It can be order of magnitude more expensive.
它可能会贵上一个数量级。
Just to give you a sense, the latency,
只是为了让你有个概念，延迟时间，
the latency to memory is maybe between 50 nanoseconds
内存的延迟可能在50纳秒左右。
and 100 nanoseconds.
和100纳秒。
The latency to read and write from a disk
从磁盘读取和写入的延迟
can be in milliseconds.
可以用毫秒表示。
So what, it's three, four order of magnitude.
那又怎样，这是三、四个数量级的差距。
Okay?
好的。
So it's huge difference.
所以这是一个巨大的差别。
So that's how you avoid,
这就是你避免的方法，
you try to minimize the number of times
你试图尽量减少次数。
you write data back to the storage, to the disk.
你将数据写回存储器，写回磁盘。
I see.
我明白了。
So this is a question,
这是一个问题，
it seems that I like when the page fault happens
似乎我喜欢页面错误发生的时候
for the first time, it tries a program again
第一次，它再次尝试一个程序。
after the man paging,
在男子寻呼之后，
instead of killing the program right away.
不要立即终止程序，而是...
But on a debug, we often see page fault message.
但是在调试过程中，我们经常会看到页面错误的消息。
The page fault message you are seeing
您所看到的页面错误消息
when you are debugging is different.
当你在调试时是不同的。
That is, for instance, when you are going to try to access
这是，例如，当你要尝试访问时。
some invalid region on the memory, right?
内存上有一些无效的区域，对吗？
Something you didn't allocate, for instance.
你没有分配的东西，例如。
Then you have page fault, right?
那么你就会出现页面错误，对吗？
It's like you just have an address
就像你只是有一个地址一样
which doesn't belong to one to read
哪一个不属于一个人阅读
or write to another address
或者写到另一个地址。
which doesn't belong to the program
这个不属于该程序。
because it's not allocated yet.
因为它还没有被分配。
So that's different.
那就不一样了。
This page fault I was talking about
这个页面错误我刚才提到的。
is not visible to the programmer.
程序员无法看到。
This happens under the hood.
这是在幕后发生的。
And what you said is correct.
你说的是正确的。
That is only this page fault happens.
这只是这个页面发生的错误。
Yes, you are going to do a trap,
是的，你打算设下一个陷阱，
then exception, trap to the operating system.
然后发生异常，陷入操作系统。
The operating system gets a page from the disk,
操作系统从磁盘中获取一个页面。
put in the memory, and then you retry it
将其存入内存，然后重试
and you restart the program from the same instruction.
然后你从同一个指令重新启动程序。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
So remember we want to provide,
所以记住我们想要提供，
with virtual memory,
使用虚拟内存，
the illusion of infinite physical memory.
无限物理内存的幻觉。
So this is one example.
这是一个例子。
Virtual memory is huge.
虚拟内存非常大。
It's 40 gigabytes.
这是40千兆字节。
You have 32 bits addresses.
你有32位的地址。
But now most of the machines,
但现在大部分的机器，
even including your phone, has 64 bits.
即使包括你的手机在内，也有64位。
So it's huge amount of memory, of virtual memory.
所以这是大量的内存，虚拟内存。
There is no way you can have a physical memory
你无法拥有物理记忆。
large enough to call the entire virtual memory
足够大，可以称之为整个虚拟内存。
of an application.
一个应用程序的。
And then you map these kind of pages
然后你将这些类型的页面进行映射。
from the virtual memory using the page table
从虚拟内存中使用页表
to the physical memory.
到物理内存。
And then some of the page,
然后页面的一部分，
which are not fitting the physical memory,
不适合物理内存的部分。
are going to be on the disk.
将会在光盘上。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the text you want to be translated.
And why is that?
为什么呢？
Because of course the disk is much higher,
因为当然，磁盘要高得多。
even as ST is much larger than a physical memory.
即使ST比物理内存大得多。
So you have a lot of more space.
所以你有更多的空间。
And it's again,
又一次，
going to the disk and getting the page.
去磁盘获取页面。
So demand paging happen transparently.
所以需求分页是透明发生的。
Okay.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
It's not visible to the application.
应用程序无法看到它。
The only way the application may notice
应用程序注意到的唯一方式是
is that it's a little bit slower.
这是因为它稍微慢一些。
Because you need,
因为你需要。
instead of getting the data directly from memory,
不直接从内存中获取数据，
you have to go first to the disk,
你首先要去磁盘。
move the data into memory,
将数据移入内存中。
and then get the data.
然后获取数据。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese into English and any non-Chinese into Chinese. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
So,
所以，
this is a page table entry.
这是一个页表项。
If you remember from two lectures ago,
如果你还记得两节课之前的内容，
you have the page frame numbers,
你有页面框架号码。
the first is 32 bits addresses, address.
第一个是32位地址，地址。
The first page,
第一页，
the page frame number,
页框号码
this represent the surface 20 bits,
这代表了20个位的表面。
and the last 12 bits are some,
而最后的12位是一些内容。
a bunch of bits of,
一堆碎片，
and each bit has a different semantics.
并且每个位都有不同的语义。
And for the purpose of this lecture,
为了这次讲座的目的，
we care about two bits.
我们关心两个方面。
One is p,
一个是p。
which is called present or valid.
哪个被称为现在或有效。
And this basically says that the page,
而这基本上是说这个页面，
the corresponding page is in memory.
对应的页面已经在内存中了。
If p is zero, the bit is zero,
如果p为零，则该位为零。
then the page is not in memory,
那么该页面不在内存中。
some are on the disk.
有一些在磁盘上。
And d is a dirty bit.
并且d是一个脏位。
And this says that the page has been modified recently.
这里写着页面最近被修改过。
So it's been modified since it was brought in memory,
所以自从它被存入内存以来，它已经被修改过了。
for example.
例如。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So this means that,
这意味着，
why do you think,
你为什么这样认为？
how do you think you are going to use a dirty bit?
你认为你会如何使用脏位？
Why do we need it?
我们为什么需要它？
It's exactly,
没错，
it's to determine, yeah,
这是要确定的，是的。
it's if you need to write the page back,
如果你需要重新写这一页的话，
if we need to,
如果我们需要的话，
if we have to replace that page,
如果我们必须替换那个页面，
because we don't have,
因为我们没有，
we no longer have room in the physical memory
我们的物理内存已经没有空间了。
to bring a new page,
翻译结果：带来一个新的页面。
then if the page we want to replace has been modified,
那么如果我们想要替换的页面已经被修改了，
we need first to write to the disk,
我们首先需要将其写入磁盘。
not lose the information.
不要丢失这些信息。
That's great.
太好了。
So this is a demand paging mechanism,
这是一个需求分页机制。
it's very simple.
这很简单。
Again, it's like repeating it.
再说一遍，就像是重复一样。
You look at the PTE,
你看一下PTE考试。
page table entry of the page.
页表项的页。
If the bit of the PTE is valid,
如果PTE的位有效，
then the means that the page in memory,
那么这意味着页面在内存中，
so you go and access the data from the memory.
所以你去访问内存中的数据。
If it's not valid,
如果它无效的话，
then this means that the page is not in memory,
那么这意味着该页面不在内存中。
it's on the disk.
它在磁盘上。
And when you do that,
当你这样做的时候，
you, this results in a trap.
你，这导致了一个陷阱。
It's a page fault.
这是一个页面错误。
And on page fault,
当发生页面错误时，
you choose an old page to replace,
你选择了一个旧页面来替换。
if you don't have enough room in the memory.
如果你的内存空间不足。
If that old page has a dirty bit set,
如果那个旧页面的脏位被设置了，
this means that you have to write that page to the disk.
这意味着你需要将那个页面写入磁盘。
And then once you are done with that,
然后一旦你完成了那个，
you also need to invalidate the PTE entry for the page,
你还需要使页面的PTE条目无效。
because now you are going to remove from the,
因为现在你要离开了，
you are going to remove it from the memory,
你将把它从内存中删除。
and also you need to invalidate the TLB entry for that page.
并且你还需要使该页面的TLB条目无效化。
And once you are done with it,
完成之后，
you are going to bring the new page from the disk memory,
你将从磁盘内存中加载新页面。
in place of the old page.
替代旧页面。
And once you bring the new page,
并且一旦你带来了新的页面，
you update the PTE of the new page,
你更新了新页面的PTE。
and you are ready to go.
你已经准备好了。
And by the way, when this happens,
顺便说一下，当这种情况发生时，
an operating system is doing all this kind of work
一个操作系统正在进行所有这些工作。
to bring the page from the disk to memory.
将页面从磁盘加载到内存。
It's a lot of IO, and in the meantime,
这是很多输入输出，同时也是这样。
you try to schedule and run other processes,
你试图安排和运行其他进程，
which are not blocked.
哪些没有被封锁。
So what are the origins of the paging?
寻呼的起源是什么？
And the origin of the paging dates long time ago,
而寻呼的起源可以追溯到很久以前，
from the '70s.
从70年代开始。
And in the '70s,
在70年代，
it was a time before everyone has a personal computer.
那是每个人都拥有个人电脑之前的时代。
And what you have, you have a terminal.
你所拥有的是一个终端。
It looks like a computer, but it's just a terminal.
它看起来像一台电脑，但实际上只是一个终端。
And they are connected to the computers.
他们与计算机相连。
You have many people running their programs
你有很多人在运行他们的程序
on the same computer,
在同一台电脑上，
and they are using the computer from these terminals.
他们正在使用这些终端上的电脑。
And now, because you have so many users,
现在，由于你有这么多用户，
and the physical memory was quite small,
而且物理内存非常小，
again, not all the users' programs could fit in
再次强调，不是所有用户的程序都能适应。
the memory.
记忆。
So now you need to,
所以现在你需要，
you need the ability to swap
你需要有交换的能力。
and to put some of these pages,
并将其中一些页面放置，
of these pages which are not used often,
这些页面中有哪些很少使用的？
or they haven't used for a while,
或者他们已经有一段时间没有使用了，
to put them on the disk, right?
把它们放到磁盘上，对吗？
So this is what happened early on.
这是早期发生的事情。
That's why you have paging.
这就是为什么你有分页功能。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
So,
所以，
and this is basically the model you have,
这基本上就是你所拥有的模型。
we should, you know,
我们应该，你知道的，
we are going to have in mind,
我们会记在心里，
and we are going to discuss,
我们将要讨论，
continue to discuss the demand paging
继续讨论需求分页。
for the rest of the lecture.
剩下的讲座。
Now, what happens when the PC is,
现在，当电脑处于...时会发生什么？
with the personal computers?
使用个人电脑吗？
Actually, with personal computers,
实际上，使用个人电脑，
initially you don't have virtual memory.
最初你没有虚拟内存。
You have one program only running on a machine,
你的机器上只有一个程序在运行，
and that program taking the entire physical memory.
并且该程序占用了全部的物理内存。
However, as personal computers became more
然而，随着个人电脑的普及，越来越多的人开始使用电脑进行工作和娱乐。
and more sophisticated,
更加复杂和精细化的。
and you run multiple programs on the same computer,
你在同一台电脑上运行多个程序，
now you're still, you are back in square one,
现在你还是停下来了，你回到了原点，
because like we discussed several times,
因为就像我们多次讨论过的那样，
the aggregate memory required by all processes,
所有进程所需的总内存
all the application running at a given time,
所有在给定时间运行的应用程序，
exceeds the physical memory.
超出了物理内存。
So again, what is the solution here?
那么，这里的解决方案是什么？
We need to virtualize the memory,
我们需要虚拟化内存。
and you need to keep some of this memory
并且你需要保留一部分这些记忆。
of this application on the disk.
这个应用程序在磁盘上的位置。
The memory, hopefully, which is not accessed very often.
希望不经常访问的内存。
Of course, all these now machines
当然，所有这些现在的机器
are connected to the cloud,
连接到云端。
all of your phones and laptops,
你们所有的手机和笔记本电脑，
and you have the same situation in the cloud, right?
你在云端也有同样的情况，对吗？
The cloud, you have very powerful computers,
云计算，你拥有非常强大的计算机，
and they run a lot of applications,
而且他们运行了很多应用程序，
and they also obviously use virtual memory.
他们显然也使用虚拟内存。
So this is, again, if you look at one machine,
这是说，如果你再看一个机器的话，
if you do the PS program status,
如果你查看PS程序状态，
this is kind of what you get.
这就是你得到的结果。
And here I'm just showing the memory
而这里我只是展示记忆。
in this particular case is pretty utilized.
在这种特殊情况下非常常用。
It says that you have certain gigabytes of memory used,
它显示你已经使用了一定的千兆字节的内存。
and only 2.7 is not used,
并且只有2.7没有被使用。
so it's more than 80% it's used.
所以使用率超过80%。
And some of them is shared memory.
其中一些是共享内存。
Remember that different application can share memory.
记住，不同的应用程序可以共享内存。
For instance, if they use the same libraries,
例如，如果他们使用相同的库，
they share the code of those libraries,
他们共享那些库的代码。
because it doesn't make sense to make a copy
因为复制没有意义
of the same code for each of the application.
每个应用程序使用相同的代码。
So there are many uses of virtual memory
虚拟内存有很多用途。
and demand paging.
和需求分页。
Remember that in the virtual memory,
请记住，在虚拟内存中，
one segment you have is a stack,
你有一个片段是一个堆栈。
and the stack grows downwards
并且栈向下增长
from the high addresses to the low addresses.
从高地址到低地址。
And as you allocate and to push more data on the stack,
当你分配并将更多数据推入堆栈时，
you may have to extend the stack.
你可能需要扩展堆栈。
So this is how you are going to do it.
这就是你要做的方式。
If you are going to want to expand the stack,
如果你想要扩展堆栈，
then it's again what will happen.
那么接下来会发生什么。
You have a page fault,
你发生了一个页面错误。
and you are going to go to the operating system,
然后你要去操作系统，
and the operating system is going to increase
并且操作系统将会增加。
the size of the stack, okay?
栈的大小，好吗？
And allocate more memory for that stack.
并为该堆栈分配更多的内存。
Another way is process fork.
另一种方式是进程分叉。
We discuss about that.
我们讨论这个。
Here we are going to rediscuss again.
我们这里要重新讨论一下。
When you do a fork,
当你进行分叉时，
you remember that the child process
你记得那个子进程吗？
has the same code as the same instance,
具有相同代码的是相同实例。
and it has the same resources as the parent process, okay?
并且它拥有与父进程相同的资源，好吗？
But because you have the same code,
但是因为你们有相同的代码，
one simple solution will be you copy the entire code
一个简单的解决方案是你复制整个代码。
and the data from the parent process to the child process
和来自父进程的数据传递给子进程
before you can start the child process.
在你可以启动子进程之前。
Of course, the problem is that this will take a lot of time.
当然，问题在于这将会花费很多时间。
So instead, what you do here is that
所以在这里，你所做的是
when you create the child process,
当你创建子进程时，
you create it immediately,
你立即创建它。
and you have it point to all the memory
并且你需要将它指向所有的内存。
of the parent process, so they share the same memory.
父进程的子进程会继承父进程的内存空间，因此它们共享相同的内存。
The only difference is that
唯一的区别是
from the point of view of the child process,
从子进程的角度来看，
all the memory is marked as read-only, no writes, right?
所有的内存都被标记为只读，不能写入，对吗？
And now when you read, everything is perfect, right?
现在当你阅读时，一切都完美了，对吗？
Because you are going to read the same content,
因为你将要阅读相同的内容，
which is not modified as from the parent.
这个没有从父级进行修改。
But now if the child wants to modify a piece of data,
但是现在如果孩子想修改一条数据，
then because the pages are read-only,
那么因为这些页面是只读的，
then it's going to cause a trap, an exception.
那么它将会引发一个陷阱，一个异常。
It's going to be intercepted by the operating system.
它将被操作系统拦截。
And the operating system now is going to copy the page,
并且操作系统现在要复制这个页面，
read-only page, it's going to create another copy now
只读页面，现在将创建另一个副本。
for the child, and now it's going to give access
给孩子，现在将提供访问权限。
to write to its own copy of that page to the child, right?
将该页面的副本写入子页面，对吗？
So when you exec,
当你执行时，
you only bring in parts of the binary in active use,
你只使用活跃的二进制部分。
you'll just bring a few pages in the memory,
你只需要将几页内容存储在内存中，
you don't bring the entire program into memory
你不需要将整个程序加载到内存中
because that can be too big.
因为那可能太大了。
And some parts of the program you may never touch
还有一些程序的部分可能你永远不会接触到。
when you are running it.
当你在运行它时。
The similarly with the stack,
与堆栈类似，
you can extend the heap and so forth.
你可以扩展堆等等。
This is another example about an animation about what happens when you, it's an end-to-end example and showing you what happens when you start a new program.
这是另一个关于一个动画的例子，它展示了当你启动一个新程序时会发生什么。
So you have a new program, the program is on the disk, it's typically, you know, it's got an extension and you have the code, you have some data, static data and some other information.
所以你有一个新的程序，这个程序在磁盘上，通常它有一个扩展名，你有代码，还有一些静态数据和其他信息。
Okay, so you need to bring that in memory, you need to bring the code in memory in order to run. And when you are going to start, you are going to bring some part of the code in memory and then you are going to bring some data in memory and then you are going to allocate heap and the stack for that particular program.
好的，所以你需要将代码加载到内存中才能运行。当你开始时，你需要将代码的一部分加载到内存中，然后将一些数据加载到内存中，然后为该特定程序分配堆和栈空间。
And this is the view from the virtual address space, VAS stands for virtual address space of the process, which was instantiated to run the program.
这是虚拟地址空间的视图，VAS代表进程的虚拟地址空间，它被实例化来运行程序。
And let's see, and then you obviously are going to back all these virtual addresses, everything in the virtual address, which is used by the program, you are going to be backed into the disk.
然后，你显然会将所有这些虚拟地址备份，即程序使用的所有虚拟地址都会被备份到磁盘上。
Finally, between the virtual address and the memory, you need to do the translation, the translation is done with the page table. Some entries from the page table are going to point to pages in the physical memory.
最后，在虚拟地址和内存之间，你需要进行翻译，这个翻译是通过页表完成的。页表中的一些条目将指向物理内存中的页面。
And if a page table, you know, it's invalid, so it doesn't exist in memory, the corresponding page table entry is going to point to the location of that page on the disk.
如果一个页表无效，也就是说它在内存中不存在，那么相应的页表项将指向该页在磁盘上的位置。
So fundamentally what you need to do if that page is on the disk is to have a function, something like that, it's a find block which takes an argument, the process ID and the page number of that.
所以基本上，如果该页面在磁盘上，你需要做的是有一个函数，类似于这样，它是一个查找块，接受一个参数，即进程ID和页面号。
And then for that page number and the process ID, you are going to get a disk location on the disk where you can find that page.
然后，对于该页码和进程ID，你将获得一个在磁盘上的磁盘位置，你可以在那里找到该页。
So this is very similar with the page table concept.
所以这与页面表的概念非常相似。
Okay. But it is purely done purely in software.
好的。但这完全是通过软件完成的。
No TLD, no nothing like that.
没有顶级域名，也没有任何类似的东西。
And why do you think the PID? Why do you take the argument, the PID argument here?
我认为PID是为什么？为什么你在这里提到PID的论点？
Anyone?
有人吗？
Because the virtual address space is per process.
因为虚拟地址空间是每个进程独立的。
Okay.
Sure, I'll do my best to assist you with your translations. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
The page tables are per process.
页面表是每个进程的。
So if I give you only the page number, it's not well defined, because multiple processes, they can have the same page numbers.
所以如果我只给你页码，它并不明确，因为多个进程可能具有相同的页码。
And because the page number represents something in their virtual address space, and each of them has a different virtual address space.
而且由于页码代表着它们在虚拟地址空间中的位置，而每个进程都有不同的虚拟地址空间。
Okay.
Sure, I'll do my best to help you with the translations. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you'd like me to translate.
So that's why you need to give the process identifier to identify the virtual address space.
所以这就是为什么你需要提供进程标识符来识别虚拟地址空间的原因。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
Where do you store it? Obviously you want to store it in memory, because if you store it on the disk, then you need to bring it from the disk. It's going to be even slower.
你把它存储在哪里？显然你想把它存储在内存中，因为如果你把它存储在磁盘上，那么你需要从磁盘中读取它。这样会更慢。
And that's pretty much it.
这就是大致的内容。
So,
所以，
any questions?
有任何问题吗？
So like in the case of the shared memory, we also can share the disk between different applications, processes.
所以就像在共享内存的情况下，我们也可以在不同的应用程序、进程之间共享磁盘。
So for instance, I'll show you next.
所以，例如，我接下来会给你展示。
And the way I'll show you that is like for instance here, again, this is virtual address space for one process, and you can have another process and another process will have its own virtual address space, its own Pi page table.
而我将向您展示的方式是，例如在这里，这是一个进程的虚拟地址空间，您可以有另一个进程，另一个进程将有自己的虚拟地址空间，自己的Pi页表。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
And here it's about the stack and the heap and the data of the second process.
这里是关于堆栈、堆和第二个进程的数据。
And assume that the second process and the first process running the same program.
并假设第二个进程和第一个进程运行相同的程序。
So the two processes that are just two instances of the same program. So in this particular case, as you can see, the code is shared, because the code is read only.
所以这两个进程只是同一个程序的两个实例。所以在这种特殊情况下，正如你所看到的，代码是共享的，因为代码是只读的。
So if you have two programs, which use instances, or sorry, it's you have two instances of the same program, then the virtual address space of the two, the two instances, the two processes, they can share the same code.
所以如果你有两个程序，它们使用实例，或者抱歉，你有两个相同程序的实例，那么这两个实例的虚拟地址空间，这两个实例，这两个进程，它们可以共享相同的代码。
And they can share the same code, obviously, and you can share also, we can share the same old code also in the physical memory.
他们可以共享相同的代码，显然，你也可以共享，我们也可以在物理内存中共享相同的旧代码。
Make sense?
有意义吗？
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Okay.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
And again,
再一次，
the page table, the second process, some of the pages have been memory, some of them, the ones which are not in memory are backed on disk.
页表，第二个进程，其中一些页面已经在内存中，其中一些页面不在内存中，它们被存储在磁盘上。
Okay.
Sure, I'll do my best to assist you with your translations. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
Now, say the process active, the first process is active, then if you are going to have fetching instruction on access some physical memory, then you look at the page table, if say the page table entry is invalid, then you have a page fault, the operating system
现在，假设进程处于活动状态，第一个进程处于活动状态，如果你要访问某个物理内存来获取指令，那么你需要查看页表。如果页表项无效，就会发生页错误，操作系统会处理这个错误。
is a block on the disk which contains the page, and then move it to
是一个包含页面的磁盘块，并将其移动到
the memory.
记忆。
Okay.
Sure. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
This is another summary step by step of handling a page fault.
这是处理页面错误的另一个逐步摘要。
Again, you access the memory,
再次，你访问了内存。
virtual memory, this is step one, say the associated page table entry is invalid. This results in a trap page fault to the operating system.
虚拟内存，这是第一步，说关联的页表项无效。这会导致操作系统触发一个陷阱页错误。
This block, locate the block where the page is stored on the disk, brings the page in memory in a free frame, page frame, updates the page table entries and restart the instruction.
这个块，定位页面在磁盘上存储的块，将页面加载到空闲的内存帧中，更新页面表项并重新开始执行指令。
Okay, a few announcements.
好的，有几个公告。
The Hallmark 4 has been released.
Hallmark 4已经发布。
This week, please attend the design reviews. Remember the design review starts at the hour.
本周，请参加设计评审会议。记住设计评审会议将于整点开始。
They are not on the Berkeley time.
他们没有按照伯克利时间来。
Please.
请。
So give time to everyone, so they can get the feedback from the TA.
所以给每个人时间，这样他们就可以从助教那里得到反馈。
Remember that you need to participate during design reviews. Part of your grade is based on that.
请记住，你需要在设计评审中参与。你的成绩的一部分是基于此的。
And other than that, you know, I know that there are now many deadlines, there are no deadlines for the next two weeks, but the next following weeks on November 1 will be pretty brutal.
除此之外，你知道，我知道现在有很多截止日期，接下来两周没有截止日期，但11月1日之后的几周将非常紧张。
So, as such, please, please make progress on homework for Project 2 and start studying about midterm 2, which is mostly the materials we are learning.
所以，请务必在项目2的作业上取得进展，并开始学习关于期中考试2的内容，这主要是我们正在学习的材料。
We have been learned since the first midterm. So midterm 2 will still have some of, you know, like maybe 10-20% for the materials of midterm 1.
我们从第一次期中考试开始就一直在学习。所以第二次期中考试仍然会包含一些第一次期中考试的内容，大概占总分的10-20%左右。
But this means that 80-90% of the materials will be from the lectures since midterm 1.
但这意味着80-90%的材料将来自于第一次期中考试以后的讲座。
Okay.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So now let's switch the gears and answer the following key question.
现在让我们转换一下思路，回答以下关键问题。
During a page fault, you need to bring a page from the disk to the memory.
在页面错误时，你需要将一个页面从磁盘加载到内存中。
How do you find room for that page?
你如何找到那一页的位置？
And if there is no room, like we discussed, we are going to find a page. If it is dirty, save it on the disk and replace it with a new page.
如果没有空间，就像我们讨论过的那样，我们会找到一个页面。如果它很脏，就将其保存在磁盘上，并用一个新的页面替换它。
But typically this is quite expensive.
但通常这相当昂贵。
You know, writing page, bring a page in is very expensive. So what many operating systems do in the background,
你知道，写入页面、将页面带入内存是非常昂贵的。所以许多操作系统在后台做的是，
they kick off some of the, they write back some of the dirty pages to the disk.
他们将其中一些脏页写回磁盘。
So if you need to replace one, then you don't need to write it back.
所以如果你需要替换一个，那么你就不需要将它写回去。
So this is kind of periodically the cleaning process.
这是一种定期的清洁过程。
So to reduce the overhead of the demand paging.
为了减少需求分页的开销。
Now, but even if you have this,
现在，即使你有这个，
you know, this background mechanism, you still need to answer the following question.
你知道，这个背景机制，你还需要回答以下问题。
Which pages are you going to write to the disk? Or which pages you are going to evict to bring a new page in?
你要将哪些页面写入磁盘？或者你要驱逐哪些页面以便引入新的页面？
OK. And the way you think about that, as you know by now, when we talk about scheduling and so forth,
好的。就你所知，当我们谈论到日程安排等事情时，你对此的看法是什么？
you need to come up with a policy. And when you come up with a policy to dictate which guides,
你需要制定一项政策。当你制定一项政策来规定哪些指南时，
which pages are written back or are evicted from the main memory,
哪些页面被写回或从主存中驱逐出去了？
there are certain properties you want, you know, you need to think about. About utilization.
有一些你想要的特性，你知道的，你需要考虑一下。关于利用率。
You want to have high utilization of the memory because it's a scarce resource.
你希望内存的利用率高，因为它是一种稀缺资源。
You may want fairness between different processes. Or you want to enforce priority.
您可能希望不同进程之间有公平性。或者您想要强制执行优先级。
So that's kind of you keep in mind that we are not going to implement different policies here.
非常感谢您记住我们不打算在这里实施不同的政策。
But this is for you to keep in mind that these are typical questions you are going to be faced with when you are going to design a page replacement policy.
但是你需要记住，这些是你在设计页面置换策略时常见的问题。
So the key model you have in mind when you run a program, one of these models, it's about the working set.
当你运行程序时，你心中所拥有的关键模型之一就是工作集。
So that what is the working set? A working set, roughly speaking, is the set of addresses whose content,
那么什么是工作集？工作集，简单来说，是一组地址，其内容在一段时间内被活动使用。
if you have in the physical memory, then the programs works well. There are very few page faults.
如果你在物理内存中有足够的空间，那么程序会正常运行。页面错误很少。
If any. Right. And this tried to show a depiction of a, this is for a program on the x axis, you have the time.
如果有的话。对的。这试图展示一个描述，这是为了一个在x轴上的程序，你有时间。
And on the y axis, you have the address. And each rectangle, the height of the rectangle represents what addresses are accessed at a given time by the program.
在y轴上，你有地址。每个矩形的高度表示程序在给定时间访问的地址。
And the length represents for how long you access content from these addresses.
而长度代表了您从这些地址访问内容的时间长度。
So this is, and as you can see here, this is execution, this red stuff, it's execution of the program. And at different times, you have different working sets.
所以这是，正如你在这里看到的，这是程序的执行，这个红色的东西，它是程序的执行。在不同的时间，你有不同的工作集。
So working set here is that if you draw a vertical line at a given time, then everything, all the blue rectangle, this line intersects,
所谓的工作集是指如果你在某个特定的时间画一条垂直线，那么这条线与之相交的所有蓝色矩形，
represent the working set, represent the addresses whose content should be in the physical memory, so that we do not have page faults.
表示工作集，表示应该在物理内存中的内容的地址，以便我们不会发生页面错误。
Okay. And the working set, one property in general is that is much smaller than the entire address space of the program.
好的。而工作集，一般来说，一个特性是它比程序的整个地址空间要小得多。
And also is changing over time.
而且也在不断变化。
And obviously you can keep all the working set in memory or in the cache, then is great. The hit rate will be one.
显然，你可以将所有的工作集保存在内存或缓存中，这样就很好了。命中率将会是100%。
If you cannot, then the hit rate will not be one, and you are going to have also some miss rates.
如果你不能做到，那么命中率就不会是100%，你也会有一些失误率。
This also shows the cache size, how much of the program is stored in the cache for this previous example.
这也显示了缓存大小，即该程序在缓存中存储了多少内容，针对这个先前的示例。
And you start with very little, and you have here a lot of, and the hit rate is also very low.
你从很少的东西开始，而你这里有很多，而且命中率也很低。
Sorry, let me backtrack here. So on the x axis here is a cache size, right? So you are looking here at caches of different sizes.
抱歉，让我回过头来解释一下。这里的x轴是缓存大小，对吗？所以你在这里看的是不同大小的缓存。
On the y axis, you have the hit rate. If the cache size is infinite, the hit rate will be one.
在y轴上，你有命中率。如果缓存大小是无限的，命中率将为1。
So when the cache size, or in other words, when the cache size is larger than the working set,
当缓存大小，或者换句话说，当缓存大小大于工作集时，
or the working set is in the cache, then the hit rate is one.
或者工作集在缓存中，那么命中率为1。
And then if the cache size is very small, then the hit rate will be very little, because probably all the working set will be,
然后，如果缓存大小非常小，那么命中率将非常低，因为很可能所有的工作集都会被覆盖。
doesn't fit in the cache. So any fetch of an instruction, every access of the data will result on, it is going to result in a miss.
不适合缓存。因此，对指令的任何获取，对数据的每次访问都会导致缓存未命中。
Okay, any questions here?
好的，这里有什么问题吗？
So if the cache is shared between different processes, like it's a second level cache, then you need to feed multiple working set in the same cache.
所以如果缓存在不同进程之间共享，比如它是一个二级缓存，那么你需要在同一个缓存中提供多个工作集。
And actually this figure shows when you have multiple working sets in the same cache. Each of these inflection points is when a new working set is feeding in the cache.
实际上，这个图表显示了当你在同一个缓存中有多个工作集时的情况。每个拐点表示一个新的工作集进入缓存。
Okay.
Sure, I'll do my best to assist you with your translations. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So obviously you are going to have a very similar behavior for demand paging. Demand paging is just caching.
所以显然，对于需求分页，你将会有非常相似的行为。需求分页只是缓存。
Now, when we are talking about the working set, we have this kind of nice model, like I mentioned that actually the program is spending most of the time or all the time in a relatively small region of the address space.
现在，当我们谈论工作集时，我们有这样一个很好的模型，就像我提到的，实际上程序大部分时间或全部时间都在地址空间的一个相对较小的区域内。
And this makes the cache very effective.
这使得缓存非常有效。
However, there are other models for locality, like Ziffian distribution.
然而，还有其他的局部性模型，比如Ziffian分布。
And in this case, yes, you do have, this is for instance, on this figure what you see, here is a rank. So this represents, say, think about each of these is a page.
在这种情况下，是的，你确实有，比如说，在这个图上你看到的是一个排名。所以这代表着，假设每个都是一个页面。
And there are pages are ranked in the decreasing order of their popularity about how often they are accessed. And the popularity of access is on the y axis.
并且这些页面按照它们被访问的频率从高到低进行排名。访问的流行度在y轴上表示。
So this says that the first page is accessed 20% of the time you access a memory, you access the first page.
这意味着每次访问内存时，有20%的概率会访问到第一页。
This is what it says.
这是它的内容。
Now, the problem with this distribution and this popularity is shown by the blue line.
现在，这个分布和这个受欢迎程度的问题可以通过蓝线来展示。
The problem with this one is that with this distribution is a very challenging distribution is that it also has a long tail.
这个问题是，这个分布的挑战在于它还有一个长尾。
Yes, most of the access are on a very few pages, but there is some pages, a lot of pages, a huge amount of pages are accessed frequently.
是的，大部分的访问都集中在很少的几个页面上，但也有一些页面，很多页面，大量的页面经常被访问。
And this creates problems, because, you know, no matter, you know, even if you have a big cache, you are still going to have misses because of this very rare items.
这会造成问题，因为，你知道的，无论你有多大的缓存，由于这些非常罕见的物品，你仍然会遇到缺失。
So what this shows you is that even if you have a small cache, you get quite a bit of value because a few pages are responsible for most accesses.
所以这表明，即使你有一个小的缓存，你也能获得相当大的价值，因为只有少数页面负责大部分访问。
The second thing is that if you have a very large cache, it's a diminishing return, it may not benefit a lot, you still have substantial misses.
第二个问题是，如果你有一个非常大的缓存，那么它的回报会递减，可能不会有太多好处，你仍然会有相当多的缺失。
Okay, questions.
好的，有问题吗？
I don't know that video but yeah, there are many situations in which you are going this distribution is very common. One is web pages.
我不知道那个视频，但是是的，有很多情况下你会遇到这种分发方式非常常见。其中一个是网页。
I'm talking about web pages, right, when you access the web pages, they have a VPN distribution.
我在说网页，对吧，当你访问网页时，它们有一个VPN分发。
And...
而且...
is very common. It's a population of cities. There are a few cities with very large population and a few of them, but there are many, many, many of them with a smaller population.
非常普遍。这是城市的人口。有一些人口非常庞大的城市，也有一些人口较少的城市，但是有很多很多很多人口较小的城市。
So it's a very common situation.
所以这是一个非常常见的情况。
So cost model, again, what we care about is estimated access time. And the estimated access time is a hit rate times hit time. So this is the latency to access the data in memory,
因此，成本模型中，我们关心的是预计的访问时间。而预计的访问时间是命中率乘以命中时间。所以这就是访问内存中数据的延迟时间。
plus miss rate plus the miss time. And the miss time is the time it takes to bring the data in memory from the disk if it's not there.
加上缺失率再加上缺失时间。而缺失时间是指如果数据不在内存中，则从磁盘中将数据带入内存所需的时间。
And it's not there because we missed.
而且它不在那里是因为我们错过了。
The hit rate plus the miss rate, as you know, is one. You can also rewrite the equation by having miss penalty by denoting miss time minus hit time.
命中率加上失误率，正如你所知，等于1。你还可以通过将失误时间减去命中时间来重新表达这个方程，以表示失误惩罚。
This is the overhead, do it to miss. This is miss penalty. So you can rewrite the equation and hit time plus miss rate times miss penalty.
这是开销，要避免它。这是失误惩罚。因此，你可以重新写出方程，命中时间加上失误率乘以失误惩罚。
And here is a very simple example. Memory access time is 200 nanoseconds. Average page fault service time, so bringing the page from the disk into memory, it's 8 milliseconds.
这是一个非常简单的例子。内存访问时间为200纳秒。平均页面错误服务时间，即将页面从磁盘加载到内存中，为8毫秒。
Let's say p is the probability of miss, 1 minus p is the probability of hit.
假设p是未命中的概率，1减去p就是命中的概率。
So this means that, and we are using the same, the second equation, the access time estimated access time is 200 nanoseconds plus p times 8 million nanoseconds.
所以这意味着，我们正在使用相同的第二个方程，估计的访问时间是200纳秒加上p乘以800万纳秒。
So if just one out of 1000 pages, page access, it's a fault.
所以如果在1000页中只有一页访问出现问题，那就是一个故障。
So this is 0.1%. The access time is over 8 microseconds, or 40 times more than just accessing the memory.
所以这是0.1%。访问时间超过8微秒，比仅仅访问内存多了40倍。
So the slowdown is huge. So if you want to have a slowdown only by 10% to 10% slowdown, then you can, you know, fit this in the equation.
所以这个减速是巨大的。所以如果你只想减速10%到10%的话，那么你可以将这个放入方程中。
And the p is the probability of miss should be lower than one page in 400,000 accesses.
而且p是错过的概率应该低于在400,000次访问中错过一页。
Okay. So that gives you a sense about how important is a page replacement policies in minimizing the miss rate. And that's how you use this, it's right here is an example.
好的。这样你就能了解页面置换策略在减少缺失率方面的重要性。这就是你使用它的方式，这里有一个例子。
And of why here the demand paging is fully associative, right, because you just want to avoid any misses at any cost.
为什么这里的需求分页是完全关联的呢，对吗？因为你只是想以任何代价避免任何缺失。
Oh, it's a question here, what is the intuition behind why the hit rate is higher for the lower ranks?
哦，这里有一个问题，为什么低排名的命中率更高的直觉是什么？
So here, right, let me see.
所以，这里，对，让我看看。
So actually, the rank is a rank of popularity.
所以实际上，这个排名是一个受欢迎程度的排名。
Right. So actually, these pages are ordered in the decreasing order of their popularity.
对的。实际上，这些页面是按照它们的受欢迎程度降序排列的。
So the rank is equal to the popularity. So there is nothing subtle here.
所以排名等于受欢迎程度。所以这里没有什么微妙的地方。
Okay. So rank doesn't mean anything else than being, you know, a measure of popularity.
好的。所以“rank”除了作为一种受欢迎程度的衡量标准外，并没有其他含义。
Okay, again, see, remember about caching. What are the type of misses, compulsory misses? So pages that have never been paid into memory, this is when you start the program, you need to read the code, right, for instance.
好的，再说一遍，记住缓存的事情。缺失的类型有哪些，强制性缺失？这是指从未被加载到内存中的页面，比如当你启动程序时，需要读取代码，对吧。
Capacity misses, you don't have enough memory. What do you do in this case?
容量不足，您的内存不足。在这种情况下，您会怎么做？
You know, obviously, you can increase the number, increase the memory size, or, you know, you can share the memory between processes and give each process certain, you know, amount of memory.
你知道，显然，你可以增加数量，增加内存大小，或者，你知道，你可以在进程之间共享内存，并给每个进程一定的内存量。
So in some cases, as you'll see, one solution is to kill one of the processes. So the remaining processes, they have enough physical memory.
所以在某些情况下，正如你所看到的，一个解决方案是终止其中一个进程。这样剩下的进程就有足够的物理内存了。
Conflict misses, you don't have those, technically, because it's a fully associative cache, right? And policy misses, it's about depends on the replacement policy we are going to use.
冲突缺失，你没有这些，从技术上讲，因为这是一个完全关联的高速缓存，对吗？而策略缺失，这取决于我们将要使用的替换策略。
So here we just want a better replacement policy to minimize the misses.
所以在这里我们只是想要一个更好的替换策略来最小化缺失。
Okay. So page replacement policies.
页面置换策略。
It's again, you know, those, you know, you know, you learn a few of them last time.
又是那些，你知道的，你知道的，上次你学了几个。
The same is similar here.
这里的情况相似。
FIFO.
先进先出。
First in, first out, you throw out the oldest page, you evict the oldest page.
先进先出，你丢弃最旧的页面，你驱逐最旧的页面。
It's some degree of fairness in terms of access.
这是在访问方面的某种程度上的公平。
But it can be also bad. Why, when it's FIFO bad? It's when you have a very popular page which is accessed over and over again, right?
但它也可能是不好的。为什么，当它是FIFO不好的时候？是因为你有一个非常受欢迎的页面，被反复访问，对吗？
And this is also one of the pages which are going to be the oldest.
这也是即将成为最古老的页面之一。
You know, could be the oldest or the program started, it loaded this page, like, for instance, the code, like for this PowerPoint slides, right?
你知道，可能是最早或者程序开始时，它加载了这个页面，比如说，代码，比如这个PowerPoint幻灯片，对吗？
The code which is responsible for going from one slide and displaying the next slide.
负责从一个幻灯片切换到下一个幻灯片的代码。
And this, I'm, you know, I am using that code from the beginning of the lecture. So that was one of the first pieces of code which was loaded in memory.
而这个，我，你知道的，我一直在使用那段代码从讲座开始。所以那是最早加载到内存中的代码之一。
But if I use FIFO, that will be also a piece of code which will be evicted.
但是如果我使用先进先出（FIFO）算法，那么这也将是一个将被驱逐的代码片段。
And if you're evicted, you know, it's just to be loaded again next time I'm turning to the next slide.
如果你被驱逐了，你知道，下次我翻到下一页时，只是重新加载。
Random is very simple.
随机很简单。
And so they're very fast to implement also in hardware. And typically you have this in TLB when you need to be super fast.
所以它们在硬件中也非常快速实现。通常，在需要超高速度时，TLB中会使用这种技术。
On the downside, it's random. It's not predictable, right?
缺点是它是随机的。它是不可预测的，对吗？
And then it's minimum. And the minimum, it's the optimal one, right?
然后它是最小的。而最小的，就是最优的，对吗？
What is the optimal replacement policy? You should know that from cash. What is the optimal replacement policy?
最佳的替换策略是什么？你应该从现金中了解到这一点。最佳的替换策略是什么？
You want to replace the page which won't be used for the longest time.
你想要替换掉那些最长时间不会被使用的页面。
It's as simple as that. The problem with this is that you need to predict the future and you don't know.
就是这么简单。这个问题的困难在于你需要预测未来，而你并不知道。
And the way around it is to use the past as a good predictor of the future. That is, if a page has not been used for a while,
而解决这个问题的方法是利用过去作为未来的良好预测指标。也就是说，如果一个页面已经有一段时间没有被使用了，
then the page will not, I assume that the page will not be again accessed for a while.
那么页面将不会被访问，我假设页面在一段时间内不会再次被访问。
And if the page was just used before recently, it's going to be likely used again in the future.
如果这个页面最近刚被使用过，那么将来很可能会再次被使用。
Any questions here?
这里有什么问题吗？
Okay, so this is approximation of min, it's recently used, right? Just replace the page that hasn't been used for the longest time.
好的，所以这是最小值的近似值，是最近使用的，对吗？只需替换最长时间未使用的页面即可。
And if the programs have every locality, this is a pretty good policy.
如果这些计划覆盖到每个地区，那这就是一个相当不错的政策。
How we implement it? One, you can simply implement it, you can keep a list of pages.
我们如何实施它？一种方法是，你可以简单地实施它，你可以保持一个页面列表。
And when you have a new page, when you access a page, you put it as a head, you move it to the head of the cube.
当你有一个新页面时，当你访问一个页面时，你将它放在头部，你将它移动到立方体的头部。
And the last in this list is a page which hasn't been accessed for the longest time.
这个列表中的最后一个是一个很长时间没有被访问过的页面。
It's a great question. Is there anything you can do when you are writing code to help decrease page misses?
这是一个很好的问题。在编写代码时，有什么方法可以帮助减少页面失效呢？
It's a great question. Yes, you can do it. I'll give you one example.
这是一个很好的问题。是的，你可以做到。我会给你一个例子。
Like for instance, and this is used and known by people, you know, do high performance computing.
比如，这是被人们使用和了解的，你知道的，进行高性能计算。
Say you have a matrix and say you want to multiply the matrix or do some operation on the matrix.
假设你有一个矩阵，并且你想要对该矩阵进行乘法运算或其他操作。
You can iterate on rows or you can iterate on columns.
你可以按行迭代，也可以按列迭代。
Now, it's very important about how this matrix is stored in memory.
现在，关于这个矩阵在内存中的存储方式非常重要。
You store row by row, you store first the first row, then the next row and the next row.
你逐行存储，先存储第一行，然后是下一行和下一行。
And if the matrix is large, if I want to grid set all the elements of the matrix, if I can, I'm going to iterate by row, it's going to have a good cache locality.
如果矩阵很大，如果我想要对矩阵的所有元素进行网格设置，如果可以的话，我会按行迭代，这样可以获得良好的缓存局部性。
So with the first row matrix, I'm already going to start to bring the first page. The first page contains a lot of elements from the first row.
所以，根据第一行矩阵，我将开始带来第一页。第一页包含了很多来自第一行的元素。
So they are going to be all already in the cache when I'm going to access them.
所以当我要访问它们时，它们都将已经在缓存中。
Okay. Now, say I'm going to write the same program, but I'm going to access columns.
好的。现在，假设我要编写相同的程序，但我要访问列。
I'm going to access the first element and I'm going to bring a page in. Now, the next element I'm going to access is going to be from the next row, not in the same row.
我要访问第一个元素，并将一个页面带进来。现在，我要访问的下一个元素将来自下一行，而不是同一行。
So the next row that can result in another miss and I need to bring another page just to access only one element from that page and so forth.
所以下一行可能导致另一个错误，并且我需要再获取另一页，只为了访问该页的一个元素，依此类推。
But by the time I go back to access the second element from the first row, that page may be already gone.
但是当我回去访问第一行的第二个元素时，那个页面可能已经消失了。
Right. Because not all the pages may fit in cache. So that's what you can do. That's one example.
对的。因为并不是所有的页面都能适应缓存。所以这就是你可以做的。这是一个例子。
You want or the TLDR here, you want to write your program to preserve locality.
你想要TLDR（总结）还是你想要编写程序以保持局部性？
Another way, another thing which kind of destroy locality, if you have go tos, right, if you write a program, it jumps around the go to. That destroys the code locality.
另一种方式，另一件破坏局部性的事情是，如果你使用了go to语句，当你编写程序时，它会跳来跳去。这破坏了代码的局部性。
I know that a large number of random accesses on the heap is generally bad for cache hit rates, but that's the same generally applies to minimize page misses.
我知道在堆上进行大量的随机访问通常会降低缓存命中率，但同样也适用于减少页面缺失。
I mean, it's again, it's like random is not going, you use random because it's fast.
我的意思是，又是这样，就好像随机不起作用一样，你使用随机是因为它快速。
But in this particular case, because it's so costly to the page fault is so costly, you really want to avoid random.
但在这种特殊情况下，由于页面错误非常昂贵，你真的想要避免随机。
And we still TLB use random because you want to be extremely, extremely fast. Right.
我们仍然使用随机的TLB，因为我们希望非常非常快速。对吧。
That happens actually in hardware. Hopefully I answered this question. If I didn't answer, you know, ask, ask it again and maybe rephrase what you think I may have missed from your question.
这实际上是硬件问题。希望我回答了这个问题。如果我没有回答，你知道，再问一次，可能重新表达一下你认为我可能在你的问题中忽略的部分。
What does this mean? We have to take a software fault on every access. Yes, this I think refers to the examples I gave you about matrices going by columns.
这是什么意思？我们在每次访问时都必须处理一个软件故障。是的，我认为这指的是我给你的关于矩阵按列进行操作的例子。
Yes. In the worst case, this means that you can take us a page fault on every access to a record.
是的。在最坏的情况下，这意味着每次访问记录时都可能发生页面错误。
No, it's either you're not. It's because it's again, it's like if you have something which is used very often,
不，要么你不是。这是因为，就好像你有一样经常使用的东西，
then every time when you access it, you are going to again, when you put here in this example, sorry, when you put here in this example, is again, if I access page seven, I'm going to put it as a head of the queue.
每次你访问它时，你都会再次这样做，当你在这个例子中放置它时，抱歉，当你在这个例子中放置它时，是再次这样做的，如果我访问第七页，我会将它放在队列的头部。
Or the head of the list accessing page one, I'm going to put it ahead of the list. Accessing page two now the page three is going to head of the list. So, and if I access something very often,
或者列表访问的第一页，我将把它放在列表的前面。现在访问第二页，第三页将会放在列表的前面。所以，如果我经常访问某个东西，
then they are going to be close to the head of the list. So they are not going to be removed. They are not going to be evicted.
那么他们将会接近名单的前面。所以他们不会被移除。他们不会被驱逐。
So, that's a good question. Does that mean that we have to work all PTEs and scans valid bits every so often to build the list? It's a great access piece, use piece, the use piece. You are referring to the use piece.
那么，这是一个很好的问题。这是否意味着我们需要定期处理所有的PTE和扫描有效位，以建立列表？这是一个很好的访问部分，使用部分，使用部分。你在提到使用部分。
That's a good point. You could do that. But as we are going to see next,
这是一个很好的观点。你可以这样做。但是接下来我们要看到的是，
this is a precise implementation of the list recently used, but it's expensive to implement.
这是最近使用列表的精确实现，但实现起来很昂贵。
So what we are going to implement, it's an approximation of Alerio.
我们要实现的是Alerio的一个近似版本。
Right. That's what we are going to implement.
好的，这就是我们要实施的计划。
So, but before we go there and we are going to show how we are going to implement an approximation of Alerio.
所以，在我们去那里之前，我们将展示我们将如何实现Alerio的近似。
And again, we want to implement an approximation of Alerio because we don't want to manipulate pointers to do many, many more accesses whenever we access a page.
而且，我们想要实现一个Alerio的近似版本，因为我们不想在访问页面时频繁操作指针来进行更多的访问。
Before that, let's look at a few other replacement policies. This is FIFO. And here we have a cache which has three slots, or you know, you have three frames.
在此之前，让我们先看一下其他几种替换策略。这是先进先出（FIFO）。这里有一个具有三个插槽的缓存，或者说你有三个帧。
And this is your order in which we access, the sequence we access these pages. As the pages are denoted A, B, C, D, there are four pages.
这是我们访问页面的顺序，按照我们访问的顺序排列。页面用A、B、C、D表示，总共有四个页面。
So I'm going to first access A's and B's and C and so forth.
所以我首先要访问A、B、C等等。
So let's access A. Initially the cache or memory is empty. So we are going to save, use the first page frame to store A.
所以让我们访问A。最初，缓存或内存是空的。所以我们要使用第一个页面框来存储A。
Then B still have available slot, available frames. I'm going to use the second one and then use a server.
然后B仍有可用的插槽和可用的框架。我打算使用第二个插槽，然后使用一个服务器。
Okay. Now things become interesting here. Now I'm going to come to access A again and A it's already in. So it's fine. I'm happy.
好的。现在事情变得有趣了。现在我要再次访问A，而A已经在里面了。所以没问题，我很开心。
I'm not going to do anything. I'm going to access it. It's already in memory. B is the same, but now it's D. D is not in the memory.
我不打算做任何事情。我要访问它。它已经在内存中了。B是一样的，但现在是D。D不在内存中。
So what do I need to do? And the memory is full. So I need to make room for it. So which page I'm going to evict here? It's first in, first out.
那么我需要做什么呢？而且内存已满，所以我需要为其腾出空间。那么我要驱逐哪一页呢？按照先进先出的原则。
So I'm going to evict the page, which was the first, which was the first which was brought in the memory, right? Which is A.
所以我要驱逐页面，这是第一个，这是第一个被带入内存的，对吗？这是A。
So I'm going to replace it with D. Now, after D it's A. Well, now A is again, the memory is full.
所以我打算用D来替换它。现在，在D之后是A。嗯，现在A又满了，内存已经满了。
So I need to pick a page to evict. And I'm going to pick which one? B. Okay. Now the next one is D again.
所以我需要选择一个页面来驱逐。我要选择哪一个？B。好的。现在下一个是D。
It's in memory. Now I don't need to do anything. Then B. Now I don't have B in memory. In memory I have only A, C and D.
它在内存中。现在我不需要做任何事情。然后是B。现在我在内存中没有B。在内存中，我只有A、C和D。
Right? So I need to replace one. So which one was the oldest? It's C. Okay. So and then C, I'm going to replace D.
对吗？所以我需要替换一个。那么哪一个是最旧的？是C。好的。然后C，我要替换成D。
And then finally B. B is already in. So here, how many pagefalls I had? One, two, three, four. Right?
然后最后是B。B已经在里面了。所以在这里，我有多少个页面掉落？一个，两个，三个，四个。对吗？
These are capacity misses. And in addition to that, I have three other misses and these are what kind of misses are those?
这些是容量不足的问题。除此之外，我还有三个其他问题，那些是什么类型的问题？
Compulsory misses. So I have three compulsory misses, four capacity misses, seven false. Seven misses. Okay.
强制性错过。所以我有三个强制性错过，四个容量错过，七个错误。七个错过。好的。
And here, just notice that this was a bad decision to replace A when we brought D in because the next access was to A.
在这里，只是注意到当我们引入D时，替换A是一个错误的决定，因为下一个访问的是A。
So let's keep this in mind and with that, I'll stop here and we are going to continue to discuss about the page replacement policies next lecture.
所以让我们记住这一点，我就到这里了，下一节课我们将继续讨论页面置换策略。
Thank you.
谢谢你。